A Finding Aid to the Polly Thayer (Starr) papers, 1846-2008, bulk 1921-2008, in the Archives of American Art AAA.thaypoll
Archives of American Art
- Sketchbooks, 1930-circa 1970; Series 11; 0.3 Linear feet Box 19, 23
  - Oversized Sketchbook of Portraits and "Sketches from the fights" from Box 19, Folder 13, circa 1933 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Artwork, 1927-circa 1990; Series 12; 0.4 Linear feet Box 19, 23, OV 25
  Artwork consists of loose sketches and drawings of animals, landscapes, and people. The artwork is in various mediums such as pencil, ink, paint and charcoal. With the exception of one drawing by a fellow art student, all of the artwork in the series is by Polly Thayer.
  - Figure Drawings at the Art League of New York, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    Oversized material housed in Box 23, Folder 4.
  - Miscellaneous Sketches, circa 1930-circa 1990 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Figure Drawings, circa 1930-circa 1950 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    Oversized material housed in OV 25.
  - Prints of Drawing at Arts Students League of NY, 1931 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    Oversized material housed in Box 23, Folder 5.
  - Portraits of Theodore Spencer, Lewis Galantiere, and May Sarton, circa 1931 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    Oversized material housed in Box 23, Folder 6.
  - Caricature of Polly Thayer by Fellow Student at Fontainebleau Art School, 1932 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    Oversized material housed in Box 23, Folder 7.
  - "Techniques" Sketches and Drawings, circa 1940-circa 1970 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    Oversized material housed in Box 23, Folder 8.
  - Pencil Drawings of Statues in Park, circa 1950 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Drawing of Cat, circa 1950-circa 1980 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Sketches of Siamese Cat, circa 1950-circa 1980 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Drawing of Polar Bears, circa 1950-circa 1990 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    Oversized material housed in Box 23, Folder 9.
  - Preliminary Sketches for Ocean Paintings, circa 1950-circa 1990 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Poster Designed by Polly Thayer for 2 Plays by Archibald Macleish, circa 1953 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    Oversized material housed in Box 23, Folder 10.
  - "Game Drawings" Sketches for Word Games, circa 1985 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Oversized Figure Drawings at the Art League of New York from Box 19, Folder 16, 1927 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Prints of Drawing at the Art Students League of New York from Box 19, Folder 19, 1931 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Portraits from Box 19, Folder 20, circa 1931 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Caricature of Polly Thayer from Box 19, Folder 21, 1932 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Oversized "Techniques" Sketches and Drawings from Box 19, Folder 22, circa 1940-circa 1970 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Drawing of Polar Bears from Box 19, Folder 26, circa 1950-circa 1990 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Oversized Posters Designed by Polly Thayer from Box 19, Folder 28, circa 1953 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Oversized Figure Drawings from Box 19, Folder 18, circa 1930-circa 1950 (Box OV 25)
- Photographs, 1898-2006; Series 13; 2.1 Linear feet Box 19-21, 24
  The four disbound binders are at the start of the series and are arranged by subject (the original binder titles were retained): portraits of women, portraits of men, landscapes, and "mystical, flowers, animals." The personal photographs are organized by subject, then chronologically within each grouping. Photographs of Polly Thayer are first, followed by photographs of family members arranged alphabetically, and then other subjects. Miscellaneous photographs are grouped together at the end of the series.
  Photographs include four disbound binders of photographs of artwork such as portraits of women, portraits of men, landscapes, and “mystical,flowers,animals.” The portrait photographs include a label with the sitter's name and sometimes the date and the name of the owner/buyer of the portrait. The other photographs of works of art also have labels with identification information.
  Also found are several folders of personal photographs which include portraits of Polly Thayer and family members, houses and properties, social events, pets, and friends. There is also one small disbound photograph album with images of houses and properties.
  - Portraits of Women Disbound Binder, circa 1930-2000 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    Oversized material housed in Box 24, Folder 1.
  - Portraits of Women Disbound Binder, circa 1930-2000 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Portraits of Women Disbound Binder, circa 1930-2000 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Portraits of Men Disbound Binder, circa 1930-2001 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Portraits of Men Disbound Binder, circa 1930-2001 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Portraits of Men Disbound Binder, circa 1930-2001 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Landscape Disbound Binder, 1936-1992 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Landscape Disbound Binder, 1936-1992 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Landscape Disbound Binder, 1936-1992 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Landscape Disbound Binder, 1936-1992 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - "Mystical, Flowers, Animals" Disbound Binder, circa 1925-1996 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - "Mystical, Flowers, Animals" Disbound Binder, circa 1925-1996 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - "Mystical, Flowers, Animals" Disbound Binder, circa 1925-1996 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - "Mystical, Flowers, Animals" Disbound Binder, circa 1925-1996 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - "Mystical, Flowers, Animals" Disbound Binder, circa 1925-1996 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Polly Thayer (Box 20)
    - Photographs Album of Polly Thayer in Agamemnon, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Childhood Photographs, 1905-circa 1913 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      Oversized material housed in Box 24, Folder 2.
    - Portraits of Polly Thayer, circa 1925-circa 1950 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      Oversized material housed in Box 24, Folder 3.
    - Photographs of Polly Thayer, 1964-1978 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Portraits of Polly Thayer taken by Steven Trefonides, circa 1985 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Photographs of Polly Thayer, 1980-1999 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Photographs of Polly Thayer, 2000-2006 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Family Photographs, circa 1910-1987 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    This folder contains group photographs of Starr and Thayer family members and relatives. Polly Thayer is in some of the photographs.
    Oversized material housed in Box 24, Folder 4.
  - Cercle Francais Group Portrait, 1924 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    Oversized material housed in Box 20, Folder 21.
  - Starr, Dinah, 1954-1995 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    Oversized material housed in Box 24, Folder 6.
  - Starr, Donald Carter (Box 20)
    - Childhood and Family Photographs, 1898-circa 1925 (Box 20, Folder 23)
      Photographs of Donald Starr with his parents and siblings.
    - Solo Photographs and Portraits, 1932-1984 (Box 20, Folder 24)
      Oversized material housed in Box 24, Folder 7.
    - Photographs with Others, 1934-1984 (Box 20, Folder 25)
      Photographs of Donald Starr with Polly Thayer and friends.
  - Starr, Victoria Thayer, circa 1945-circa 1960 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Thayer, Eleanor Arnold, circa 1916-circa 1921 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Thayer, Ezra Ripley, circa 1910 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Thayer, James Bradley, The Younger, 1905 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Friends and Colleagues, circa 1931-2004 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Pets, circa 1964-2005 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - "Painting Sites", circa 1963-1990 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - "Elsinore" House, 1928 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Weir River Farm, circa 1929-1996 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - 77 Bay State Road, circa 1960 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - West Chop Summer House, circa 1970-1988 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - 198 Beacon Street, circa 1985 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Dismantled Album of Several Houses, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Hingham House, 1936-1996 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in Box 24, Folder 8.
  - Bust of Polly Thayer by Agnes Yarnall, 1937-2001 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Oversized Binder Cover of Portraits of Women from Box 19, Folder 30, circa 1995 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    The original binder cover was retained b/c there are extensive annotations on the verso with the names of portrait subjects and the names and addresses of the portraits' owners.
  - Oversized Binder Cover of Portraits of Men from Box 20, Folder 1 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Childhood Photograph of Polly Thayer from Box 20, Folder 14, circa 1913 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Portraits of Polly Thayer from Box 20, Folder 15, circa 1925-circa 1950 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Photograph of Cousin's Wedding from Box 20, Folder 20, circa 1920 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Cercle Francais Portrait from Box 20, Folder 21, 1924 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Dinah Starr Photograph from Box 20, Folder 22, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Donald Starr Portrait from Box 20, Folder 24, circa 1980 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Oversized Photograph of Hingham House from Box 21, Folder 10, circa 1950 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Photo of Bust from Box 21, Folder 11, circa 1937 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Photograph of Carving from Box 21, Folder 12, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 8)